Finding Aid for the Collection of Broadside Ballads from England, Ireland, and the United States LSC.0605
UCLA Library Special Collections
- England
  - Walker, George and George Walker, Jun. (Going-Outlaw), ca. 1797-1886
    - Moon is on the water. Donald's return to Glencoe. The moon is on the water. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: W7; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Moon is on the water. Donald's return to Glencoe. Donald's return to Glencoe. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: W7; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Newfoundland dog. Little fools and great ones. Russell, Henry, 1812-1900, Little fools and great ones. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: 6:2:17; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 26 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Newfoundland dog. Little fools and great ones. Russell, Henry, 1812-1900, The Newfoundland dog. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: 6:2:17; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 26 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Oh saw ye the lass wi' the bonny blue e'en. When I was young and fair. The American serenaders. When I was young and fair. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: 6:3:16; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Oh saw ye the lass wi' the bonny blue e'en. When I was young and fair. The American serenaders. Ryan, Richard, 1796-1849, Oh saw ye the lass wi' the bonny blue e'en. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: 6:3:16; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Oh saw ye the lass wi' the bonny blue e'en. When I was young and fair. The American serenaders. The American serenaders. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: 6:3:16; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Our ancesters were Englishmen. The morn was gay. The morn was gay. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: 6:5:12; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Our ancesters were Englishmen. The morn was gay. Our ancesters [sic] were Englishmen. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: 6:5:12; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Outlaw. Squire and thrasher. Squire and thrasher. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: 6:6:4; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Outlaw. Squire and thrasher. The outlaw. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: 6:6:4; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Walker, George and George Walker, Jun. (Prime-Ye), ca. 1797-1886
    - Prime the cup, fill it high. The boatman of de Ohio. De color'd fancy ball. Emmett, Daniel Decatur, 1815-1904, The boatman of de Ohio. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: 6:10:8; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Prime the cup, fill it high. The boatman of de Ohio. De color'd fancy ball. Prime the cup, fill it high. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: 6:10:8; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Prime the cup, fill it high. The boatman of de Ohio. De color'd fancy ball. De color'd fancy ball. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: 6:10:8; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Queen's anthem. The hairy cap. Rodger, Alexander, 1784-1846, The Queen's anthem. Durham, England; G. Walker Jun. Printer, Sadler-Street, Durham, [between 1834 and 1886]., Shelfmark: 6:10:13; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 18 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Queen's anthem. The hairy cap. The hairy cap. Durham, England; G. Walker Jun. Printer, Sadler-Street, Durham, [between 1834 and 1886]., Shelfmark: 6:10:13; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 18 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Reconciling kiss. The reconciling kiss. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: 6:12:5; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 9 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Sailor's farewell. The rover of the seas. The rover of the seas. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: 6:15:12; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Sailor's farewell. The rover of the seas. The sailor's farewell. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: 6:15:12; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Sammy Slap the Bill Sticker. The maniac. Sammy Slap the Bill Sticker. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1834 and 1886]., Shelfmark: 6:16:8; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 26 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Sammy Slap the Bill Sticker. The maniac. Lewis, M. G. (Matthew Gregory), 1775-1818, The maniac. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1834 and 1886]., Shelfmark: 6:16:8; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 26 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Sheffield apprentice. A maiden sought the dewy grove. The sheffield apprentice. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: 6:18:1; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Sheffield apprentice. A maiden sought the dewy grove. A maiden sought the dewy grove. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: 6:18:1; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Slave chase. Kathleen Mavourneen. The brave old oak. The star of Glengary. Chorley, Henry Fothergill, 1808-1872, The brave old oak. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: 8:1:5; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Slave chase. Kathleen Mavourneen. The brave old oak. The star of Glengary. Crawford, F. Marion (Francis Marion), 1854-1909, Kathleen Mavourneen. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: 8:1:5; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Slave chase. Kathleen Mavourneen. The brave old oak. The star of Glengary. Cook, Eliza, 1818-1889, The star of Glengary. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: 8:1:5; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Slave chase. Kathleen Mavourneen. The brave old oak. The star of Glengary. The slave chase. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: 8:1:5; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Slave. Brave old oak. The better land. Jefferys, Charles, 1807-1865, The slave. Durham, England; George Walker, Printer, Sadler-Street, Durham, [between 1834 and 1886]., Shelfmark: 8:1:4; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Slave. Brave old oak. The better land. Chorley, Henry Fothergill, 1808-1872, Brave old oak. Durham, England; George Walker, Printer, Sadler-Street, Durham, [between 1834 and 1886]., Shelfmark: 8:1:4; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Slave. Brave old oak. The better land. Hemans, Felicia Dorothea Browne, 1793-1835, The better land. Durham, England; George Walker, Printer, Sadler-Street, Durham, [between 1834 and 1886]., Shelfmark: 8:1:4; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Swaggering farmers. Susannah don't you cry. Swaggering farmers. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1834 and 1886]., Shelfmark: 8:5:1; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Swaggering farmers. Susannah don't you cry. Foster, Stephen Collins, 1826-1864, Susannah don't you cry. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1834 and 1886]., Shelfmark: 8:5:1; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - To the West! to the West. Isabel. The Briton's home. The bride's farewell. Mackay, Charles, 1814-1889, To the West! To the West. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: 8:8:16; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 26 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - To the West! to the West. Isabel. The Briton's home. The bride's farewell. Beevor, M. L., The bride's farewell. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: 8:8:16; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 26 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - To the West! to the West. Isabel. The Briton's home. The bride's farewell. The Briton's home. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: 8:8:16; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 26 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - To the West! to the West. Isabel. The Briton's home. The bride's farewell. Isabel. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: 8:8:16; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 26 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Water drinker. Sleep gentle lady. The Irish emigrant. The water drinker. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: 8:12:10; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 26 × 20 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Water drinker. Sleep gentle lady. The Irish emigrant. Dufferin and Clandeboye, Helen Selina, Baroness, 1807-1867, The Irish emigrant. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: 8:12:10; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 26 × 20 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Water drinker. Sleep gentle lady. The Irish emigrant. Planche…, J. R. (James Robinson), 1796-1880, Sleep gentle lady. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: 8:12:10; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 26 × 20 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - We expect about November. Little Mary of the Dee. We expect about November. Durham, England; Durham: Printed by George Walker, Jun., Sadler-Street. And sold by John Livsey 43, Hanover-Street Shudehill Manchester, [1840]., Shelfmark: 8:12:12; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 26 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - We expect about November. Little Mary of the Dee. Little Mary of the Dee. Durham, England; Durham: Printed by George Walker, Jun., Sadler-Street. And sold by John Livsey 43, Hanover-Street Shudehill Manchester, [1840]., Shelfmark: 8:12:12; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 26 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - When we went out a Gipsying. Happy land. Ransford, Edwin, 1805-1876, When we went out a Gipsying. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: 8:14:1; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 26 × 20 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - When we went out a Gipsying. Happy land. Bruton, James, 1815-1867, Happy land. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1797 and 1834]., Shelfmark: 8:14:1; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 26 × 20 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Ye mariners of England. Old Joe. Buffalo gals. Brower, F. M., Old Joe. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1834 and 1886]., Shelfmark: 8:18:1; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Ye mariners of England. Old Joe. Buffalo gals. Campbell, Thomas, 1777-1844, Ye mariners of England. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1834 and 1886]., Shelfmark: 8:18:1; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Ye mariners of England. Old Joe. Buffalo gals. Hodges, John, Buffalo gals. Durham, England; Walker, Printer, Durham, [between 1834 and 1886]., Shelfmark: 8:18:1; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Walker, William, ca. 1807-1860
    Printed in Otley, England.
    - Christmas hymns. Christmas hymns. Otley, England; Printed by William Walker, Otley, [between 1807 and 1860]., Shelfmark: 3:10:11; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 30 × 18 cm. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Waller, E., ca. 1807
    Printed in Wakefield, England.
    - Our king and our country. Our king and our country. Wakefield, England; E. Waller, Printer, Northgate, Wakefield, [1807]., Shelfmark: 6:5:14; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 27 × 15 cm. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Wardman, H., ca. 1830
    Printed in London, England
    - Kirkburton Tragedy, giving an account of the murder of Rachel Crossley, of Kirkburton, near Huddersfield, by Wm. Shaw, her sweetheart, also his apprehension, and execution at York, on the 5th of April 1830 The Kirkburton Tragedy, giving an account of the murder of Rachel Crossley, of Kirkburton, near Huddersfield, by Wm. Shaw, her sweetheart, also his apprehension, and execution at York, on the 5th of April 1830. London, England; H. Wardman, printer, 6, Chapel-Lane, Bradford, ca. 1830., Shelfmark: 11:7:1; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 51 × 38 cm. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Watts, ca. 1840
    Printed in Staffordshire, England.
    - Parson and the sucking pig: or, Pick and choose. The parson and the sucking-pig: or, Pick and choose. Staffordshire, England; Watts, Printer, Lane-End, Staffordshire Potteries, [18--]., Shelfmark: 6:6:20; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Queens marriage. John Hodge's ramble to London. Queens [sic] marriage. Staffordshire, England; Watts, Printer, Lane-End, [1840]., Shelfmark: 6:10:17; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 18 cm. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Queens marriage. John Hodge's ramble to London. John Hodge's ramble to London. Staffordshire, England; Watts, Printer, Lane-End, [1840]., Shelfmark: 6:10:17; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 18 cm. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Watts, T., ca. 1840
    - Capture of St. Jean d'Acre. The capture of St. Jean d'Acre. [Birmingham], [England]; Printed at T. Watt's, Publishing Office, [not before 1840]., Shelfmark: 3:8:15; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 24 × 17 cm. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - White, J., 18--
    Printed in Market Rasen, England.
    - Jeannot to Jeannette. Flowing hair. Down among the dead men. All's well. Dyer, John, 1700?-1758, Down among the dead men. Market Rasen, England; J. White, Printer, Market Rasen, 18--., Shelfmark: White1; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 26 × 20 cm. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Jeannot to Jeannette. Flowing hair. Down among the dead men. All's well. Flowing hair. Market Rasen, England; J. White, Printer, Market Rasen, 18--., Shelfmark: White1; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 26 × 20 cm. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Jeannot to Jeannette. Flowing hair. Down among the dead men. All's well. Jefferys, Charles, 1807-1865, Jeannot to Jeannette. Market Rasen, England; J. White, Printer, Market Rasen, 18--., Shelfmark: White1; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 26 × 20 cm. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Jeannot to Jeannette. Flowing hair. Down among the dead men. All's well. Dibdin, Thomas, 1771-1841, All's well. Market Rasen, England; J. White, Printer, Market Rasen, 18--., Shelfmark: White1; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 26 × 20 cm. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - White, John, 18--
    Printed in Liverpool, England.
    - Red plaid shawl. Termagant wife. The red plaid shawl. Liverpool, England; Printed by John White, Rose Place Liverpool, [18--]., Shelfmark: 8:7:4; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 26 × 20 cm. (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Red plaid shawl. Termagant wife. Termagant wife. Liverpool, England; Printed by John White, Rose Place Liverpool, [18--]., Shelfmark: 8:7:4; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 26 × 20 cm. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Wilkes, J., 18--
    Printed in Wellington, England.
    - Fountain. The sinner's dream. The moon shines bright. The moon shines bright. Wellington, England; J. Wilkes, Printer, Wellington, [18--]., Shelfmark: 4.7.4; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engravings); 24 × 23 cm. (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Fountain. The sinner's dream. The moon shines bright. The fountain. Wellington, England; J. Wilkes, Printer, Wellington, [18--]., Shelfmark: 4.7.4; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engravings); 24 × 23 cm. (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Fountain. The sinner's dream. The moon shines bright. The sinner's dream. Wellington, England; J. Wilkes, Printer, Wellington, [18--]., Shelfmark: 4.7.4; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engravings); 24 × 23 cm. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Williamson, W. H., ca. 1845-1850
    - Billy Nuts the Poet. Never hold malice! Never hold malice!. Newcastle, England; Williamson, Printer, Newcaslte [sic], [ca. 1845]., Shelfmark: 3:5:5; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Billy Nuts the Poet. Never hold malice! Billy Nuts the Poet. Newcastle, England; Williamson, Printer, Newcaslte [sic], [ca. 1845]., Shelfmark: 3:5:5; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Thrashing machine. Farmers don't you cry. The thrashing machine. Newcastle, England; Williamson, Printer, Newcastle, [ca. 1845]., Shelfmark: 8:7:12; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Thrashing machine. Farmers don't you cry. Farmers don't you cry. Newcastle, England; Williamson, Printer, Newcastle, [ca. 1845]., Shelfmark: 8:7:12; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Voltigeur. The Marseillaise hymn. Rouget de Lisle, Claude Joseph, 1760-1836, The Marseillaise hymn. Newcastle, England; Printed for H. Williamson, Newcastle, [1850]., Shelfmark: 8:11:12; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 26 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Voltigeur. The Marseillaise hymn. Voltigeur, the winner of the St. Ledger [i.e. Leger] and cup at Doncaster, 1850. Newcastle, England; Printed for H. Williamson, Newcastle, [1850]., Shelfmark: 8:11:12; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 26 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Wonderful shape. Edwin and Flora. The wonderful shape. Newcastle, England; Printed for W. H. Williamson, [ca. 1845]., Shelfmark: 8:16:20; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Wonderful shape. Edwin and Flora. Edwin and Flora. Newcastle, England; Printed for W. H. Williamson, [ca. 1845]., Shelfmark: 8:16:20; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Wrighton, Daniel, ca. 1812-1830
    - Bristol garland. The bristol garland. Birmingham, England; Printed by D. Wrighton, No. 86, Snow Hill, Birmingham, [between 1812 and 1830]., Shelfmark: 3:7:14; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 22 × 29 cm. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Careless Billy. Careless Billy. Birmingham, England; D Wrighton 86 Snow-Hill Birmingham, [between 1812 and 1830]., Shelfmark: 3:8:19; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 26 × 10 cm. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Colier [sic]: a new song. The colier [sic]: a new song. Birmingham, England; D. Wrighton, Printer, Snow Hill, Birmingham, [between 1812 and 1830]., Shelfmark: 3:11:10; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 26 × 10 cm. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - How sweets [sic] the love, that meets return. How sweets [sic] the love, that meets return. Birmingham, England; Printed by D. Wrighton, No. 86 Snow Hill, Birmingham, [between 1812 and 1830]., Shelfmark: 4.17.8; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 26 × 10 cm. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Merry cobler. The merry cobler. Birmingham, England; D. Wrighton, Printer, [between 1812 and 1830]., Shelfmark: Wright1; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 26 × 10 cm. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Merry sailor. The merry sailor. Birmingham, England; Printed by D. Wrighton, 86, Snow-Hill, Birmingham, [between 1812 and 1830]., Shelfmark: Wright2; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 26 × 9 cm. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Poor soldier's daughter. The poor soldier's daughter. Birmingham, England; Printed by D. Wrighton, No. 86, Snow Hill, Birmingham, [between 1812 and 1830]., Shelfmark: 6:8:20; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 26 × 10 cm. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Sup of good whiskey. A sup of good whisky. Birmingham, England; D. Wrighton, Printer, Snow Hill, Birmingham, [between 1812 and 1830]., Shelfmark: 8:4:19; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 26 × 9 cm. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Tom Starboard. Knight, T. (Thomas), d. 1820, Tom Starboard. Birmingham, England; Printed by D. Wrighton, No. 86, Snow Hill, Birmingham, [between 1812 and 1830]., Shelfmark: 8:9:6; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 26 × 10 cm. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Trumpet sounds a victory. Cherry, A. (Andrew), 1762-1812, The trumpet sounds a victory. Birmingham, England; Daniel Wrighton, Printer, Birmingham, [between 1810 and 1820]., Shelfmark: 8:9:18; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 23 × 9 cm. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Wednesbury concert. Wednesbury concert. Birmingham, England; D. Wrighton, 86, Snow-Hill, Birmigham [sic], [between 1812 and 1830]., Shelfmark: 8:13:2; 1 sheet ([1] p.): ill. (wood engraving); × cm. (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Ireland
  - Baird, J. and H., ca. 1828
    Printed in Cork, Ireland.
    - Address to the electors of Mallow. Lyons, David, An address to the electors of Mallow. Cork, Ireland; J. & H. Baird, Printers, 20, Paul-Street, Cork., [ca. 1828]., Shelfmark: 3:1:2; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 30 × 8 cm. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Erin the green. A new song called Erin the green. Cork, Ireland; J. & H. Baird, Printers, 20 Paul-St, Cork., [ca. 1828]., Shelfmark: 4.3.3; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 32 × 10 cm. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Wife's answer to The petticoat is master. The wife's answer to The petticoat is master. Cork, Ireland; J. & H. Baird, Printers, 20, Paul-Street, Cork., [18--]., Shelfmark: 8:14:12; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 32 × 10 cm. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Birmingham, W., 18--
    Printed in Dublin, Ireland.
    - Erin's lovely home. Erin's lovely home. Dublin, Ireland; W. Birmingham, 92, Thomas-st., [18--]., Shelfmark: 4.3.2; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 31 × 8 cm. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Nell Flaherty's drake. Nell Flaherty's drake. Dublin, Ireland; W. Birmingham, 92, Thomas-street, [18--]., Shelfmark: Birm1; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 29 × 7 cm. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Rambler of Clare. The rambler of Clare. Dublin, Ireland; W. Birmingham, 92, Thomas-st., Dublin, [18--]., Shelfmark: 6:11:17; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 26 × 8 cm. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Brereton, P. (Adventures-Convict), ca. 1862-1869
    - Adventure's [sic] of Roger O'Hare. The adventure's [sic] of Roger O'Hare. Dublin, Ireland; P. Brereton 1 Lr Exchange St Dublin., [ca. 1867]., Shelfmark: 3:1:5; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 29 × 11 cm. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Adventures of John Manks and his pock-marked cat. The adventures of John Manks and his pock-marked cat. Dublin, Ireland; P. Brereton 1 Lr Exchange St Dublin., [ca. 1867]., Shelfmark: 3:1:4; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 28 × 11 cm. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Annie Lisle. Thompson, H. S. (Henry S.), A new song call'd Annie Lisle. [Dublin], [Ireland]; P. Brereton, 1, Lr, Exchange St., [ca. 1867]., Shelfmark: 3:1:14; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 29 × 11 cm. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Aquital [sic] of Robert Kelly. The aquital [sic] of Robert Kelly. Dublin, Ireland; P. Brereton Printer Cook Street Dublin., [ca. 1867]., Shelfmark: 3:2:13; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 29 × 11 cm. (Box 9, Folder 3)